Guide to the Society for the Psychological Study of Lesbian and Gay Issues records, 1981-2006
Society for the Psychological Study of Lesbian and Gay Issues records, 1981-2006
- Series II. Internal Files
  - Committees and Associations
    - Committee on Gay and Lesbian Issues
      - SPSLGI minutes, correspondence, announcements, 1982-83 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - APA Policy statements on LGB Issues (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Committee on Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Concerns
      - CLGH-DMS-III-R, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Materials from CLGC meeting, Apr. 1985 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - CLGBC Annual Reports, 1996-1997, 1999, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Committee on Gay Concerns, minutes and agenda, March 1983 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Committe on Gay Concerns, minutes and agenda, Oct. 1983 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - CLGBC reports and calls for nominations, 1996-1998 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - American Psychological Association (APA)
      - Preparatory materials for APA, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - New APA Division Proposal, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - APA Resolution on Lesbian and Gay Rights (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - APA AIDS policy statement, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - APA memos, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - APA monthly reports, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Agenda: new APA division, Feb. 23, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
      - APA meeting, Dec. 4, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Readings from APA, June 24, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
      - APA meeting, June 24, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Arguments for APA meeting, June 24, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Memos from APA, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Memos from APA, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Memos from APA, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
      - APA Executive Committee, Feb. 1987 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - APA, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Background materials, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - APA Convention, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - APA Convention Office Information, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - APA - Program Chair Committee, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Materials regarding the APA amicus brief: Colorado Referendum Case (Evans vs. Romer) (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - APA Convention, Summer 1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - APA Winter EC Meeting, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - APA Convention, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - APA Convention, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - APA Convention, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - APA Accounting Monthly Statements, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - APA Statements/Taxes, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - APA Accounting Services (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - APA Officer's Handbook, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Apportionment Ballot Results/APA Election Issues, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - APA Nominations for Boards and Committees, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 44)
      - Guidelines Training: Overheads, Undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
      - Guidelines 3 Bears, 1999-07-27-1999-09-01 (Box 13, Folder 34)
      - Guidelines, 1999-07-01 (Box 13, Folder 35)
      - Guidelines, 1999-02-10 (Box 13, Folder 36)
      - COPPS Guidelines, 1994-08-14-1995-12-11 (Box 13, Folder 37)
      - Guidelines Council Agenda Item 9, 2000-02-25 (Box 13, Folder 38)
      - Governance Issues Council Strategies, 2000-02 (Box 13, Folder 39)
      - Governance Issues Consolidated Meetings Notes, 1999-10 (Box 13, Folder 40)
      - Governance Issues APA Legal Counsel, 1999-10-14 (Box 13, Folder 41)
      - BPA Treatment Guidelines Article, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 42)
      - Letters Requesting Review, 1999-05-03 (Box 13, Folder 44)
      - Guidelines Governance Conference Call BPA, 1999-07-26 (Box 13, Folder 45)
      - Governance Issues Conference Call Proposed BPA/BAPPI Conference, 1999-07-01 (Box 13, Folder 46)
      - Governance Issues Consolidated Meetings, 1999-03 (Box 13, Folder 47)
      - Summary of Conference Call, 1999-08-02 (Box 13, Folder 48)
      - Guidelines Comments, Spring 1999 (Box 13, Folder 49)
      - External Revision Round 2 Letters, 1997-11-07 (Box 13, Folder 50)
      - Guidelines E and T, Browning Paper, 2000-09-22 (Box 13, Folder 52)
      - Guidelines Training: Grossman Paper, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 53)
      - Guidelines Workshop Case I, Undated (Box 13, Folder 54)
      - Guidelines Workshop Case II, Undated (Box 13, Folder 55)
      - Guidelines Workshop Case III, Undated (Box 13, Folder 56)
      - Guidelines Workshop Case IVa, Undated (Box 13, Folder 57)
      - Guidelines Workshop Case IV, Undated (Box 13, Folder 58)
      - Guidelines Workshop Case V, Undated (Box 13, Folder 59)
      - Guidelines Workshop Case VI, Undated (Box 13, Folder 60)
      - Guidelines Training: Powerpoint, Undated (Box 13, Folder 61)
      - Guidelines: Speaker Notes, Undated (Box 13, Folder 62)
      - Guidelines: Who Will Benefit? APA Convention, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 63)
      - Guidelines Training: DIV 44 2001 EC Workshop, 2000-10-11 (Box 13, Folder 65)
      - Guidelines Training: Cal. Psych. Assoc. Proposal, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 67)
      - Calif. Psych. Assoc. Workshop Material, Undated (Box 13, Folder 68)
      - Georgia Psych. Association: Clinical and Diversity Issues, 2001-06-22 (Box 13, Folder 69)
      - Georgia Psych. Association: Ethical Implications, 2001-06-22 (Box 13, Folder 70)
      - Georgia Psych. Association: Workshop, 2001-01 (Box 13, Folder 71)
      - JTF Annotated Draft, Undated (Box 13, Folder 72)
    - Task Force on Diagnostic Concerns
      - Division 44 Task Force on Diagnostic Concerns, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Joint Council on Professional Education in Psychology (JCPEP)
      - JCPEP meeting, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 46-47)
    - Committee on Lesbian and Gay Family Issues (CLGFI)
      - Committee on Lesbian and Gay Family Issues, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Task Force on Treatment Guidelines
      - Division 44 Task Force on Treatment Guidelines (Box 8, Folder 35-39)
    - Council of Representatives (COR)
      - Military Ban: Background Materials, 1991-2003 (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Military Ban: Military, 1992-2004 (Box 9, Folder 36)
      - Military Ban: Joint Task Force on Military Discrimination, 1993-2004 (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - Military Ban: Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 38)
      - Military Ban: Council Motions, 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Concerns International Conference (LGBCIC)
      - Program Committee, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 40)
      - Grants, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 41)
      - Proposals and Rough Drafts, 1999-2000 (Box 9, Folder 42)
      - Old Budget, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 43)
      - United Airlines, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 44)
      - Funding, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 45)
      - Invitees, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 46)
      - Harrassment Letter, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 47)
      - Program, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 48)
      - Executive Committee, 1999-2001 (Box 9, Folder 49)
      - Timeline, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 50)
      - Program Inquiries and Suggestions, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 51)
      - Advisory Notices and Feedback, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 52)
      - Planning Notes, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 53)
      - Registration Materials, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 54)
      - History and Summaries, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 55)
      - New Goals, Objectives, Budget, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 56)
      - Old Purpose and Goals, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 57)
      - News Articles, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 58)
      - Division 52, Gottsegen, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 59)
      - Program Teams: Youth (Box 9, Folder 60)
      - Program Teams: Women (Box 9, Folder 61)
      - Program Teams: HIV/AIDS, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 62)
      - Program Teams: Depathologization, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 63)
      - International Lesbiand and Gay Association, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 64)
      - Delegate Nominees, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 65)
      - Board of Directors, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 66)
      - Executive Committee Meetings, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 1-6)
      - LGBCIC: Program Evaluation, 2001-09-01 (Box 13, Folder 64)
    - Joint Task Force (JTF) to write Guidelines for Psychotherapy with Gay, Lesbian, and Bisexual Clients
      - Timeline, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Guidelines Research, 1992-1999 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Midwinter/Annual Reports to the Executive Committee of Division 44, 1996-1998 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Proposed Revisions and Communications, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Guidelines (Short) Number 1, October 1997 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Guidelines (Long) Revision, November 1997 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Guidelines Revision, April 1998 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Guidelines Revision, June 1998 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Guidelines Revision, July 1998 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Guidelines Revision, September 1998 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Guidelines Revision (Berkeley), November 1998 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Shorter Form Number 2 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Savin-Williams Revisions (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Cockran Revisions, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - Kate Hays Revisions, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - Aoki Revisions, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - D'Angelli Revisions, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - Fassinger Revisions, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Stevenson Revisions (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - Guidelines Book Proposal, 1998-2001 (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - Guidelines Copies, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 27)
      - Report to Division 44 Executive Committee Meeting, August 2000 (Box 10, Folder 28)
      - Continuing Education: Guidelines Workshop, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - Council of Representatives: Update on Guidelines Activities, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 30)
      - LGBT Guidelines: 1997-2000 Paperwork (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Standards: 93 Symposium, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Symposium 95, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - 96 Convention Proposal, 1996 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Guideline Training: Paper, 2000-11-19 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Guidelines: Defining Competence Empirically - Israel et. Al., 2000-05 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Guidelines Training: Program Proposals, 2001-02-01 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Georgia Psychological Association Guidelines Workshop: Evals., 2001-06-22 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Committee Reports, 1999-05-24 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Naked Truth, Undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
        Manuscript Notes
      - JTF Draft Annotated, 1997-09-07 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - JTF Draft #3, 1997-11-05 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - JTF Draft Annotated Revisions, Undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - JTF Proposal Draft, Undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - Gonsiorek Feedback (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - Fox Review, 1997-10-13 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - Literary Review Haldeman, 1997-08-26 (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Bibliography, 1994-09-23-1996-05-22 (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - Surveys 95, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - CLGCTF Report, 1990-04-09 (Box 13, Folder 21)
      - Background Material, 1995-01-27 (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - Guidelines for Providers of Psychological Services, 1990-08 (Box 13, Folder 23)
        To Ethnic, Linguistic, and Culturaly Diverse Populations
      - Internal Revision June 98 Version, 1998-06 (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Internal Revision Fox, 1997-08-30 (Box 13, Folder 25)
      - Template for Council (Child Guidelines), 1998-02-20-1998-02-22 (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Nystrom Study, 1997-02-16 (Box 13, Folder 27)
      - Communications, 1993-02-22-1997-08-13 (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Requests for Literature, 1996-10-14 (Box 13, Folder 29)
      - Budget Fundraising, 1997-03-04-1998-08-13 (Box 13, Folder 31)
      - Symposium 94, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Accreditation
      - Mid-Winter Report, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Annual Committee
      - Publications-Volumes 4 and 5, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Bisexuality Task Force
      - Reports, August 16, 1997; January 23-25, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Continuing Education Committee
      - Reports, correspondence, and workshops, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Workshop resources, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Paperwork (workshop materials, reports, membership, etc.), 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - Fellows Committee
      - Reports, 1997-1999 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Ethnic Minority Affairs Committee
      - Reports; Div 44 and 45 Joint Sessions, 1996-1998 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Science Task Force
      - Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Student Representatives
      - Reports; Guide to APA convention, 1996-1998 (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Youth and Family Task Force
      - Reports, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 55)
- Series III. Audiotapes
  - National High Risk Youth Learning Workshop, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - APA Convention, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Public Mental Health by Terry S. Gock (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - unlabelled audiotapes (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - APA Symposium (Part 2 only): "Stigma, Human Rights, & Sexual Orientation-- International Perspectives", 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - APA Division 44 Invited Address by Don Clark, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - APA Tribute to Alan Malyon, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Series IV. Photographs
  - Division 44 photographs, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Photograph of Greg Herek at press conference, Dec. 1986 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Photgraphs and negatives from Division 44 events, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Series V. Subject Files
  - Structural Clinical Interview for DSM-III-R, May 1, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - SCID-OP copy, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - SCID, May 1, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14-16)
  - APA-DSM-III-R, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - ICD-10, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Shadow in the Land, by Congressman William Dannemeyer, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous
  - General
    - LPS quiz (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Mailing labels (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 9-17)
    - "A History of Division 44" chapter by Douglas Kimmel (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Division 44 materials (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "Healthy People 2010" publication, by the Gay and Lesbian Medical Association (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Amicus Brief, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - APA on State Anti-Gay Initiatives, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - American Psychological Association Newsletter, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - APA Resolution on Conversion Therapy, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - HRC and NGLTF on Gender Identity Disorder, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Division 44 History Paper by Douglas Kimmel and Chris Browning, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Division 44 History Paper: edits, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Maylon-Smith Award documents, 1995-1998 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Placek Award announcement, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Roy Scrivner Award, December 1997--May 1998 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous letters to Allan Pinka, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - Miscellaneous letters to Allan Pinka, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - LGB Issues in China: Correspondence between Chris Browning and Jin Wu, 1996-1998 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Members
    - Beverly Greene Certificate of Appreciation, August 16, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Catherine Acuff: Recommendation, CV, Obituary, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Roy Scrivner: Obituary, December 18, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 45)
- Series VII. Videotapes
  - APA Symposium, Part 1 (Los Angeles); Division 44: Martin, Marmor, Davidson, Silverstein (part), 1985; V-421
  - APA Symposium, Part 1 (Los Angeles); Division 44: Martin, Marmor, Davidson (Dup 1/99), V-422; (Duplicate)
  - APA Symposium, Part 2 (Los Angeles); Division 44: Morin and Hooker; Interviews with Davidson and Morin, James Harrison Interviewer., V-423; Original copy of 3/4" Master Tape
  - APA Symposium, Part 2 (Los Angeles); Division 44: Morin, Hooker, and Interviews (Dup 1/99), V-424; (Duplicate)
  - APA Division 44, Schippers, Rehm, Kimmell, Harrison. Tape 1., V-425
  - APA Division 44; Interviews by James Harrison with Jan Schippers, Jeff Rehm, Douglas Kimmell, Alan Malyon Memorial, Linda Garnets, chair; Annual Business Meeting, Adrienne Smith, chair (Dup 8/98), V-426; (Duplicate)
  - APA Division 44, Smith Welch, Garnets, Kimmell, Brown, Morin, Alan Malyon Memorial. Tape 2., V-427
  - APA, Meg Guinish Session, V-428; 3/4" Original
  - 4 SPSSOLI Spots: 2,3,4,1[?], V-429
  - APA Convention, Homeless Women Youth, Jim Weinrich - interviews, V-430
  - unlabeled, V-431
  - First Lady and then Brewster, 1990; V-432
  - APA Convention, Jim Weinrich; Camera: Sosa, sound: Abramides, Carla, 1990; V-433
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Division 44 Newsletter v. 1 no. 3 (Nov.) 1985; v. 2, nos. 1-2 (Apr.-Jul.) 1986; v. 3, nos. 1-3 (Mar.-Nov.) 1987; v. 4, nos. 1-3 (Apr.-Nov. 1988); v. 5, nos. 1-3 (Apr.-Dec.) 1989; v. 6, no. 1 (Apr.) 1990; v. 10, no. 2 (Aug.) 1994; v. 13, nos. 1-3 (Spring-Fall) 1997; v. 14, nos. 1-3 (Spring-Fall) 1998; v. 15, nos. 1-3 (Spring-Fall) 1999
Guidelines for Psychotherapy with Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Clients. Washington, D.C.: Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Concerns Committee, American Psychological Association, 2000.